Guide to the New-York Historical Society Librarian Dorothy C. Barck Records 1921-1954 NYHS-RG 19
New-York Historical Society
- 1942-1945 Correspondence. MO-MY (2 folders), 1939-1945 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 5-6)
  Includes a large amount of correspondence from John Hill Morgan dating from 1939-1944.
- 1942-1945 Correspondence. NA-New Jersey (Offsite-box 11, Folder 7)
- 1942-1945 Correspondence. New York-NO (2 folders) (Offsite-box 11, Folder 8-9)
  Frequent correspondents: Edna L. Jacobsen of the New York State Library and Robert Livingston Nicholson.
- 1942-1945 Correspondence. O (2 folders) (Offsite-box 11, Folder 10-11)
  Frequent correspondent: Beecher Ogden.
- 1942-1945 Correspondence. P-Q (3 folders) (Offsite-box 11, Folder 12-14)
  Frequent correspondent: S. K. Stevens, State Historian with the Pennsylvania Historical Commission.
- 1942-1945 Correspondence. R (3 folders) (Offsite-box 12, Folder 1-3)
  Includes a sample of Oak #13 from the Library Bureau division of Remington Rand. Frequent correspondents: Helen Wilkinson Reynolds of the Dutchess County Historical Society, Harriet M. Richards, and A. J. H. Richardson.
- 1942-1945 Correspondence. SA-SE (3 folders) (Offsite-box 12, Folder 4-6)
  Frequent correspondents: William Sawitzky and E. Gibert Schermerhorn.
- 1942-1945 Correspondence. SH-SN (2 folders) (Offsite-box 12, Folder 7-8)
  Frequent correspondents: Emily E. F. Skeel and Thomas E. Snook.
- 1942-1945 Correspondence. SO-SP (2 folders) (Offsite-box 12, Folder 9-10)
  Includes correspondence and a draft program related to the planning of the 1944 Society of American Archivists (SAA) annual meeting, which was faced with difficulties related to the war. Includes correspondence and material related to the activites of the Special Libraries Association and to Barck's involvement in the Committee on Microfilming and Documentation.
- 1942-1945 Correspondence. ST-SZ, 1942-1946 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 11)
- 1942-1945 Correspondence. TA-TH (2 folders) (Offsite-box 12, Folder 12-13)
  Frequent correspondents: Kendall B. Taft (concerning his article on a poem by Halleck in the Bulletin of April 1943), Ruth E. Thomas, and Charles E. Thorn. Includes a letter from Ted Tempest expressing his surprise and pleasure that some of his World War II letters to friends had become part of N-YHS's collection.
- 1942-1945 Correspondence. TI-TU (2 folders) (Offsite-box 13, Folder 1-2)
  Frequent correspondent: Patricia M. Tutchings, primarily concerning her donation of photographs taken by her father, Pirie MacDonald.
- 1942-1945 Correspondence. U (2 folders) (Offsite-box 13, Folder 3-4)
  Notable correspondent: R. W. G. Vail. Frequent correspondent: Captain H. A. Baldridge of the U. S. Naval Academy Museum.
- 1942-1945 Correspondence. V (Offsite-box 13, Folder 5)
  Frequent correspondents: Bayard Verplanck and Victor W. von Hagen.
- 1942-1945 Correspondence. WA-WAT (2 folders) (Offsite-box 13, Folder 6-7)
  Notable correspondent: Alexander Wall. Frequent correspondent: William F. Ward. Includes correspondence concerning N-YHS's solicitation from businesses, government agencies, and others of World War II-related posters.
- 1942-1945 Correspondence. WE-WIL (2 folders), 1940-1945 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 8-9)
  Includes a large amount of correspondence from the H. W. Wilson Company, dating 1940-1944.
- 1942-1945 Correspondence. Wegelin, Oscar (2 folders), 1940-46 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 10-11)
  Includes the outgoing correspondence of N-YHS bibliographer Oscar Wegelin, primarily reference questions and questions about the holdings of the N-YHS. Frequent correspondents: Clarence S. Brigham with the American Antiquarian Society, Nelson B. Gaskill, Charles F. Heartman, Elmer T. Hutchinson, Thomas Ollive Mabbott, Sanford A. Moss, R. W. G. Vail, and Thomas Streeter.
- 1942-1945 Correspondence. WIM-WY (2 folders) (Offsite-box 13, Folder 12-13)
  Frequent correspondent: Helen M. Wright.
- 1942-1945 Correspondence. Y-Z (Offsite-box 13, Folder 14)
  Notable correspondent: George Zabriskie.
- 1942-1945 Correspondence. Misc. A-Z, 1939-1944 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 15)
  Includes an offer by the Earl of Southesk to sell papers relating to Andrew Elliot, the last Governor General of New York. Includes request by N-YHS to mount advertisements ("car cards") in select subway lines.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. Misc. A-Z (2 folders) (Offsite-box 14, Folder 1-2)
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. American, etc. (2 folders) (Offsite-box 14, Folder 3-4)
  Frequent correspondents: Lawrence Vail Coleman, Director of the American Association of Museums, and Norman E. Webster of the American Institute of Accountants' Committee on History. Includes documents related to the American Heritage Foundation's Freedom Train. This Train traveled 33,000 miles in 1947-1948 with documents related to freedom in this country. Included in this folder is a press release and a list of documents that travelled with the train. Also includes a 1949 questionnaire from the American Historical Association about the arrangement and use of manuscript collections. The questionnaire is mostly completed with short answers.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. A-AN (2 folders) (Offsite-box 14, Folder 5-6)
  Includes list of materials from the library of Charles A. Hanna donated by his daughters.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. American Antiquarian Society (Offsite-box 14, Folder 7)
  All correspondence to or from the American Antiquarian Society. The two most frequent correspondents are Clifford K. Shipton, Librarian, and Clarence S. Brigham, Director.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. American Association for State and Local History (3 folders), 1944-1953 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 8-10)
  Includes correspondence, programs, and other materials related to the AASLH. Includes a program for the 1952 Annual Meeting at which Barck was part of a panel entitled "A Round Table Discussion of 'American Heritage.'"
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. American Fur Co. Papers (microfilming) (2 folders) (Offsite-box 14, Folder 11-12)
  Includes correspondence related to the project of microfilming the American Fur Company Papers. The Papers are on 37 reels and the cost was split between several libraries.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. AP-AZ (Offsite-box 14, Folder 13)
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. BA (3 folders) (Offsite-box 14, Folder 14-16)
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. BE (2 folders), 1945-1953 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 1-2)
  Frequent correspondent: Watson B. Berry. Notable correspondent: W. Phoenix Belknap, Jr.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. BI-BL (Offsite-box 15, Folder 3)
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. BO-BR (3 folders), 1945-1953 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 4-6)
  Frequent correspondents: Edgar Ewing Brandon and Aneita Doty Brown.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. BU-BY (2 folders) (Offsite-box 15, Folder 7-8)
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. CA-CE (2 folders) (Offsite-box 15, Folder 9-10)
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. CH-CL (2 folders) (Offsite-box 15, Folder 11-12)
  Frequent correspondent: WIlliam Bell Clark.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. CO (3 folders), 1942-1953 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 13-15)
  Frequent correspondents: Bartlett Cowdrey and Isabella Vache Cox. Includes letter from Barck to John A. Krout of Columbia University explaining N-YHS's policy of restricting undergraduate access to manuscripts.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. CR-CZ (2 folders) (Offsite-box 15, Folder 16-17)
  Frequent correspondent: T. Cruger Cuyler.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. DA (2 folders) (Offsite-box 16, Folder 1-2)
  Frequent correspondents: Curtis Carroll Davis and Richard Beale Davis.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. DE (2 folders) (Offsite-box 16, Folder 3-4)
  Frequent correspondents: Brigadier General John Ross Delafield and Gertrude Brinckle, Librarian of the Historical Society of Delaware.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. DI-DR (2 folders), 1945-1953 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 5-6)
  Frequent correspondent: Howard N. Doughty. Includes materials related to Barck's brief radio appearance in 1953 to encourage Congress to allocate funds for the restoration of Castle Clinton. The materials are a letter confirming the recording time, a speech and a play about Castle Clinton by Doris Weininger.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. DU-DY (2 folders), 1946-1954 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 7-8)
  Frequent correspondent: Margaret L. Kane for Pierre S. duPont.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. E (3 folders) (Offsite-box 16, Folder 9-11)
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. FA-FL (2 folders), 1945-1953 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 12-13)
  Frequent correspondent: William Webb, librarian with the Flint Public Library.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. FO-FY (2 folders) (Offsite-box 16, Folder 14-15)
  Frequent correspondent: Ira J. Friedman.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. GA-GO (3 folders) (Offsite-box 16, Folder 16-18)
  Frequent correspondents: Joseph Gavit, Rodman Gilder, Mrs. Louis A. Gillet, and M. J. Walsh of Goodspeed's Book Shop.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. GR-GZ (2 folders), 1946-1954 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 1-2)
  Frequent correspondent: Bruce Grant. Includes some correspondence from art historian George Groce.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. HA-HAM (Offsite-box 17, Folder 3)
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. HAN-HAZ (2 folders) (Offsite-box 17, Folder 4-5)
  Frequent correspondents: Alfred J. Hanna of Rollins College, Clifford K. Shipton of Harvard College Library, and Odell S. Hathaway. Includes a description of the Charles A. Hanna collection, with a list of books returned to the donors (see also folder HO for Mrs. W. Huntting Howell), and a list of books and manuscripts from Henry O. Havemeyer in 1945.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. HE (2 folders), 1943-1954 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 6-7)
  Frequent correspondent: Erik Heyl.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. HI (Offsite-box 17, Folder 8)
  Frequent correspondent: Nicholas B. Wainwright, Assistant Librarian at the Historical Society of Pennsylvania.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. HO (3 folders), 1942-1953 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 9-11)
  Frequent correspondents: Henry B. Hoffman, H. Maxson Holloway, Director of the Saginaw Museum, Sarah C. W. Hoppin, Dr. G. L. Howe, and Herbert Barber Howe.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. HU-HY, 1946-1952 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 12)
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. Hyer, Richard (2 folders), 1941-1952 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 13-14)
  Contains correspondence between Barck and Richard Hyer concerning his genealogical research.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. I (Offsite-box 18, Folder 1)
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. JA-JL (Offsite-box 18, Folder 2)
  Frequent correspondent: Stuart Wells Jackson.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. Jackson, Frank L., 1945-1951 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 3)
  Contains correspondence primarily about Jackson's various gifts to the library.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. JO-JZ (Offsite-box 18, Folder 4)
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. KA-KE (Offsite-box 18, Folder 5)
  Includes a letter to Katherine C. Kane in which Barck, based on research in the New York Commercial Advertiser, identifies the ten lecturers who spoke in 1852-53 as a benefit for the N-YHS Building Fund.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. KI-KO (Offsite-box 18, Folder 6)
  Frequent correspondent: Bernhard Knollenberg.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. Kinkead, George B., 1945-1949 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 7)
  Primarily outgoing correspondence from Barck to Reverend Dr. George B. Kinkead answering reference and genealogical questions.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. Knowlton, Mrs. Dexter A., 1946-1951 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 8)
  Primarily personal correspondence between Barck and Mary L. (Mrs. Dexter A.) Knowlton until Knowlton's death in 1951. Includes a letter from Knowlton's daughter, Dorothy, informing Barck of her mother's death.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. KR-KZ (Offsite-box 18, Folder 9)
  Frequent correspondent: Gracie B. Krum.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. LA, 1944-1953 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 10)
  Frequent correspondent: Bella C. Landauer.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. LE-LI (2 folders) (Offsite-box 18, Folder 11-12)
  Frequent correspondent: Edwin D. LeRoy.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. LL-LY (Offsite-box 18, Folder 13)
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. MC-MAC (2 folders) (Offsite-box 18, Folder 14-15)
  Frequent correspondents: Alice Peake MacNiece, and L. McCormick-Goodhart.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. MA-MAQ (Offsite-box 18, Folder 16)
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. MAR-MAZ (2 folders), 1943-1953 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 1-2)
  Frequent correspondent: Charles Arthur Mauer.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. ME (2 folders), 1943-1953 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 3-4)
  Frequent correspondents: Arthur H. Merritt and Jesse Merritt, Nassau County Historian.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. MI (2 folders), 1944-1953 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 5-6)
  Frequent correspondents: Charles Trinder Middlebrook and Arthur P. Miller.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. MO, 1943-1953 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 7)
  Frequent correspondent: Anne McDonnell, Assistant Librarian at the Historical Society of Montana.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. MU-MY, 1944-1953 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 8)
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. NA-NE, 1942-1953 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 9)
  Includes the April 1950 edition of Program Notes for Women's Clubs, a publication by the National Association of Manufacturers for women who plan and lead programs.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. New Jersey (Offsite-box 19, Folder 10)
  Includes an evaluation on an intern and a packet from the New Jersey College for Women, titled "Instructions for Observation on Field Work."
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. New York City. Misc. (Offsite-box 19, Folder 11)
  Frequent correspondent: Arthur S. Maynard of the New York Genealogical and Biographical Society.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. New York State Historical Association (Offsite-box 19, Folder 12)
  Contains personal correspondence and reference questions between Barck and the staff at the New York State Historical Association, in particular James Taylor Dunn, Janet MacFarlane, and Mary E. Cunningham.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. New York State Library (Offsite-box 19, Folder 13)
  Included is correspondence related to the publication of a list of Fourth of July orations, and the N-YHS sent a list of the orations they own for this publication. Also included is some correspondence and a newspaper clipping about the Freedom Train.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. New York State. Misc., 1945-1953 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 14)
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. Nicholson, Robert Livingston (Offsite-box 19, Folder 15)
  Includes personal correspondence and letters from Barck thanking Nicholson for his many small gifts to the N-YHS.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. NI-NY (Offsite-box 19, Folder 16)
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. OA-OQ (Offsite-box 20, Folder 1)
  Frequent correspondents: Herbert R. Odell and Maud O'Neil. Notable correspondent: Bartlett Cowdrey, representing the Old Print Shop and George C.D. Odell.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. Ogden, Beecher, 1946-1951 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 2)
  Primarily correspondence between Barck and Ogden about his many gifts of amateur periodicals, some personal correspondence.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. OR-OZ, 1944-1953 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 3)
  Frequent correspondent: Marion F. Overton.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. PA (Offsite-box 20, Folder 4)
  Frequent correspondent: John E. Parsons.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. PE (Offsite-box 20, Folder 5)
  Frequent correspondent: Stephen H. P. Pell (see also folder FO-FY for Fort Ticonderoga Museum).
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. Pennsylvania (Offsite-box 20, Folder 6)
  Frequent correspondent: Steve K. Stevens, State Historian, Pennsylvania.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. PF-PL (Offsite-box 20, Folder 7)
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. PO-Q (Offsite-box 20, Folder 8)
  Frequent correspondent: Clyde H. Porter.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. Princeton (Offsite-box 20, Folder 9)
  Primarily reference requests from Princeton staff, most frequently: Julian P. Boyd, editor of the Papers of Thomas Jefferson, Lyman H. Butterfield, and Mina R. Bryan.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. RA-RE (2 folders) (Offsite-box 20, Folder 10-11)
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. RH-RI (Offsite-box 20, Folder 12)
  Frequent correspondent: Ellen G. Rionda.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. RO (2 folders), 1944-1953 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 13-14)
  Frequent correspondent: Francis Rogers. Notable correspondent: Mrs. Theodore Roosevelt Jr.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. RU-RY (Offsite-box 20, Folder 15)
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. SA (2 folders), 1945-1953 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 16-17)
  Frequent correspondent: Dorothy W. Knepper, Director, San Jacinto Museum of History Association.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. SC (2 folders), 1943-1956 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 1-2)
  Frequent correspondents: William B. Efner, City Historian, Schenectady, Major E. Gilbert Schermerhorn, and H. Philip Schuyler.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. SE (Offsite-box 21, Folder 3)
  Frequent correspondent: Storrs Henry Seeley. Includes materials related to the transfer of the Seventh Regiment library to the New-York Historical Society.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. SH-SL (2 folders), 1943-1954 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 4-5)
  Frequent correspondents: Theodore Sizer of the Yale University Art Gallery and Mrs. Roswell Skeel, Jr.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. SM-SN (Offsite-box 21, Folder 6)
  Frequent correspondent: Abel I. Smith, Jr. Notable correspondent: Mary Bartlett Cowdrey, Curator, Smith College Museum of Art.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. SO-SP (Offsite-box 21, Folder 7)
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. Special Libraries Association, 1943-1953 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 8)
  Includes material related to the Special Libraries Association and Barck's involvement in that group, including her activities as Archives Chairman and Chairman of the Museum Group. Also included is a copy of the Special Libraries Assocation Constitution and By-Laws, with proposed changes; minutes of the Advisory Council Meeting on April 26, 1950; 1949 Bulletin for the Museum Group; the March 1949 issue of the New York Chapter News of the Special Libraries Association, including the program for their Spring Institute meeting on March 25 and 26 of 1949; the May 1949 Bulletin for the Geography and Map Group; and a copy of the Survey on the Storage of Microfilm in Libraries of the New York City Area, distributed by the Committee on Microfilming and Documentation, 1943-44.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. SQ-STI (2 folders), 1942-1953 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 9-10)
  Includes a partially completed list of theatre-related materials at the New-York Historical Society in response to a survey sent by Clifford E. Hamar, Acting Instructor at Stanford University. Frequent correspondent: Allan Forbes, President of the State Street Trust Company, and Madeleine B. Stern.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. STO-SZ (2 folders), 1944-1953 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 11-12)
  Included is the Abbreviated List of some of the California Gold Rush Pieces Printed in 1849 and 1850 in the TWS Collection. Frequent correspondent: George Hammond Sullivan.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. TA-TE (Offsite-box 21, Folder 13)
  Frequent correspondent: Robert Taft.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. TH (Offsite-box 21, Folder 14)
  Frequent correspondent: W. Stephen Thomas, Director, Rochester Museum of Arts and Sciences.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. TI-TY (2 folders), 1942-1953 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 1-2)
  Notable correspondent: Helen Turner. Also included is an image of Turner's painting of her studio at Cragsmoor.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. U (Offsite-box 22, Folder 3)
  Included is "The Problem of Periodical Storage in Libraries: A Possible Solution with a List of Current Periodicals Available on Microfilm for the Cost of Binding," published by University Microfilms in April 1950.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. University (Offsite-box 22, Folder 4)
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. U. S. A. -- Misc. (Offsite-box 22, Folder 5)
  Includes a letter from Vail to General Dwight D. Eisenhower requesting WWII materials to be sent to N-YHS.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. U. S. A. Naval -- Misc. (Offsite-box 22, Folder 6)
  Includes correspondence, memos, and other materials related to N-YHS's attempt to collect naval materials from the US Navy to add to their Naval History collection.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. V (2 folders), 1943-1953 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 7-8)
  Frequent correspondents: E. J. Van Lennep, Florence Van Rensselaer, Dorothy A. Plum, bibliographer at Vassar College Library, Bayard Verplanck, and Victor W. von Hagen.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. WA (2 folders), 1944-1953 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 9-10)
  Frequent correspondents: Paul A. W. Wallace of Lebanon Valley College and Myrtle V. Newton of the Wayne County Historical Society.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. WE (2 folders) (Offsite-box 22, Folder 11-12)
  Frequent correspondents: Norman E. Webster, with the American Institute of Accountants, Harry B. Weiss with the New Jersey Department of Agriculture, and Leonidas Westervelt.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. WH-WI (2 folders) (Offsite-box 22, Folder 13-14)
  Frequent correspondents: C. E. H. Whitlock, Mrs. Gordon Wightman, Edith Wilkinson, and Hermann Warner Williams, Jr. with the Corcoran Gallery of Art.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. WO-WY (2 folders) (Offsite-box 22, Folder 15-16)
  Frequent correspondents: Mrs. A. K. (W. B.) Wolcott, Charles Lennox Wright, Helen R. Wright, and Harry S. Douglass, the Wyoming County Historian.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. Y, 1942-1953 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 1)
  Frequent correspondents: Donald G. Wing and Mary C. Withington, both with the Yale University Library.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. Z (Offsite-box 23, Folder 2)
  Notable correspondents: George A. Zabriskie.
- 1946-1953 Correspondence. Misc. A-Z, 1947 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 3)
  All incoming correspondence, half of which is addressed to Mr. Carlson, a fellow N-YHS employee. The content is about copies made by the N-YHS and the payments associated.
- American Association for State and Local History, 1940 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 4)
  Minutes associated with the first meetings of the AASLH, when Barck was acting secretary-treasurer. Included are the minutes for the 36th Annual Meeting of the Conference of State and Local Historical Societies, 1940, during which the AASLH was established. Also includes C. C. Crittenden's call to action of April 1940, the impetus for the formation of the new organization.
- American Association for State and Local History, 1941 (3 folders) (Offsite-box 23, Folder 5-7)
  Includes some letters from Barck encouraging others to join the new organization; a list of individual and institutional members as of April 1941; copies of the minutes for the First Annual Business Meeting and the First Annual Council Meeting, both held on October 8, 1941; the program for the first annual meeting held on October 7 and 8, 1941; an address by C. C. Crittenden entitled "History for the People" delivered to the Pennsylvania Federation of Historical Societies in April 1941; a draft version of an article for the first bulletin written by Edward P. Alexander, entitled "What Should our Historical Society Do?"; minutes for the AASLH Council Meeting in June, 1941; several copies of the AASLH constitution; and minutes for the Fifth Council Meeting in December 1941.
- American Association for State and Local History, 1942 (2 folders), 1941-1942 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 8-9)
  Includes the program for the second annual meeting of the AASLH on October 27-28, 1942; a list of New York members and prospective members; materials related to Barck's duties as chairman of the Nominating Committee; a Statement of Income and Expenses for the year ended December 31, 1941 for the AASLH; and a copy of "A Proposed Committee on Virginia Historical Records of the Second World War," read at the Council meeting of December 1941.
- American Association for State and Local History, 1943 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 10)